<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wootton Red Team 2018</title>
    <description>Systems, Software, Security</description>
    <link>https://twlinux.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://twlinux.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>TRICKY</title>
        <description>
          Week 15 Practice Lab #2 - 
          A politician hires you to troubleshoot their private cloud storage server. It has an ordinary login webpage (HTML Form served over HTTP through default port 80), but the site refuses to connect. They have provided you with their username and password. username=hilarious password=ch33secake Objective Get the server online at http://tricky.local....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-11-tricky/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-11-tricky/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Red Team (Linux Club) Updates</title>
        <description>
          Name Change, Avahi mDNS - 
          The name of Linux Club was changed to Red Team. https://twlinux.github.io/about We will have bi-weekly challenges. These can be puzzles related to system administration or security CTFs (capture the flag). testing both your understanding of Linux and penetration testing. No more arbitrary IPv4 addresses! mDNS advertising is accomplished using Avahi....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-10-avahi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-10-avahi/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Password Validation Riddle</title>
        <description>
          Software analysis - 
          The two methods below, written in Java, check and validate username and password parameters. private final String correctUsername = user.getName(); private final String correctPass = user.getPass(); public boolean checkA(String username, String pass) { return username.equals(correctUsername) &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pass.equals(correctPass); } public boolean checkB(String username, String pass) { boolean userCorrect = username.equals(correctUsername); boolean...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-08-shortcircuit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-08-shortcircuit/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review and Reinforce</title>
        <description>
          Week 14 - Fixing the UNSAFE Server - 
          Solution to the UNSAFE Challenge is found here: https://github.com/twlinux/unsafe/blob/answer/SOLUTION.md. The server has three critical vulnerabilities (that I can think of). Brainstorm for specific ways that you can fix the server, and what other considerations you should make. Answers Outdated dependency. st@0.2.4 is vulnerable to directory traversal. Update declaration in package.json...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-06-safer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2018-01-06-safer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UNSAFE</title>
        <description>
          Week 12 &amp; 13 Practice Lab #1 - 
          This event will take place on December 19th, 2017 and also January 2nd, 2018 at 14:40. I developed the full-stack of a static web blog. Use your knowledge and creativity to crack the server! And it sucks. Your objective is simple: tamper the website. You will work in teams of...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-14-unsafe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-14-unsafe/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>White-box testing</title>
        <description>
          Week 10-11 recap - 
          Below are a few concepts which will prepare you for our competition next week. Dependencies Even if you are testing unreleased programs written in unfamiliar languages, there are publicly known vulnerabilities about the application’s dependencies. This documentation can be found easily with a search engine. OWASP Top 10 - 2017...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-13-whitebox/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-13-whitebox/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ParrotSec Linux</title>
        <description>
          Designed with Security, Development, and Privacy in mind. - 
          In our networking lab, computers in the far row that were running Vanilla Ubuntu 17.10 were replaced with Parrot Security OS. The other row still has Ubuntu Budgie. ParrotSec is less popular than Kali, though this is advantageous: MCPS has not blocked it (yet). https://parrotsec.org/ ParrotSec is based on Debian....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-01-parrot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-12-01-parrot/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Packet Sniffing</title>
        <description>
          Week 7-9 - attacking internet connections - 
          Alphabet Soup TCP/IP (Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol): a suite of communication protocols used to interconnect network devices on the internet. HTTP (Hypetext Transfer Protocol): application-layer protocol for transmitting documents. HTML (Hypertext Markup Language): describes the content of a webpage. Tracing HTTP Connections to the Internet To compromise network traffic going...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-11-14-packet-sniffing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-11-14-packet-sniffing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Man in the Middle (MitM)</title>
        <description>
          Week 5-6 - ARP Poisoning - 
          Address Resolution Protocol The address resolution protocol (ARP) resolves a IPv4 address to the corresponding MAC address. Man in the Middle (MitM) Attack telnet We will demonstrate ARP poisoning attacks against the telnet protocol. Telnet is a method of remotely accessing a server. https://github.com/twlinux/club/wiki/Remote-access#telnet Telnet is legacy software, it transmits...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-31-mitm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-31-mitm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kali Linux</title>
        <description>
          Introduction to penetration testing - 
          “Ethical hacking” describes the use of cybersecurity tools to promote “good”. Linux Club provides this content for educational use only. Please ask your victims politely before attempting to compromise their data or devices. Attempting to gain unauthorized access to any computer system is illegal. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Penetration_test A penetration test, colloquially known...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-30-kali/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-30-kali/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UNIX Systems Administration</title>
        <description>
          Week 4 - basic tasks and systemd - 
          Text mode editors It is safer to use text-mode text editors and basic utilities to manipulate system files. Set SUDO_EDITOR in your .bashrc file: export SUDO_EDITOR=rnano nano is an easy-to-understand text-mode text editor. (I actually recommend vim and SUDO_EDITOR=rvim, however vim is very advanced and is probably confusing.) rnano and...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-24-sysadmin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-24-sysadmin/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Linux environment</title>
        <description>
          GNOME, FHS - 
          Desktop environment The graphical user interface of *NIX operating systems are managed by an “X server”. GNOME 3 is the most popular desktop environment on Linux. The computers in our lab were replaced with Ubuntu 17.10, some running Ubuntu’s GNOME, and others on Budgie (which is more lightweight). The official...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-18-DE/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-18-DE/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Public Key Cryptography</title>
        <description>
          Week 3 - Asymmetric encription using GnuPG - 
          OpenPGP (Pretty Good Privacy) defines a standard of how asymmetric cryptographical algorithms can be used to encrypt and sign files. GnuPG (GNU Privacy Gaurd) is the msot common tool used on Linux for PGP. Basic concepts A private-public key pair is generated. You distribute your public key. Others use your...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-17-pki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-17-pki/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stickers and Rewards</title>
        <description>
          
          I bought some unixstickers. Unixstickers is a vendor that sells (high quality) stickers and swag (things with logos printed on it), donating a portion of the revenue to the respective open source projects. These stickers will be given as rewards for completing practice labs. Stickers table Sticker Description Arch Linux...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-16-stickers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-16-stickers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Command Line Interface (CLI)</title>
        <description>
          Week 2 - basic Linux concepts and bash - 
          From Wikipedia: A shell is a user interface for access to an operating system’s services. The most basic shell is sh. bash is the most common shell for Linux. It has many more features and is easier to use than sh, and is nearly universal. There are other less common...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-10-cli/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-10-cli/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Meeting</title>
        <description>
          Week 1 - Installation - 
          Thanks for joining Linux Club! Click here to see more information about the club itself. An introduction to Linux and Open Source Linux is an open source kernel. Coupled with the GNU software distribution, GNU/Linux is a powerful operating system that dominates the non-consumer computing market. Various distributions, or “distros”,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-03-week-one/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-03-week-one/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparation for the first meeting!</title>
        <description>
          
          We will be having our first meeting on Tuesday, the third of October. After an introduction, we’ll be starting off by installing Linux on the workstations. As a reminder, we meet in room 15. Room 15 is a computer lab, with a door to another computer lab, dubbed the “networking...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-01-first-week-prep/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twlinux.github.io//2017-10-01-first-week-prep/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
